Recursion is a process in which a method calls itself continuously, a method that calls itself is called
a recursive method.
It makes the code compact but complex to understand.
When you hear a problem, beginning with the following statements, it's often, though not always,
a good candidate for record.
Design and algorithm to compute the EMF or write code to list the first and or implement a method to
compute all and so on.
OK, so we use that for recurring recurring recursive solutions by definition are built of solution
to solve the problem.
Many times this will mean simply to compute f of and by adding something, removing something or otherwise
changing the solution for f of and minus one.
Don't worry, we are going to make recursion as simple as like making any any valuable or adding to
numbers.
Yes, trust me.
So in other cases, you might solve the problem for the first half of the dataset.
Then the second half and then merge those results.
For example.
Andrew Kurgan, we have this, for example, we have this function called B.
And contains system that are to print hello and copy sculling itself, and the system says the public
static void main.
This is the main function that is in Java.
It is executed during the runtime.
So when you print that, when you run the program, that function main would be executed.
So function main is executed, so it will call P, so it will go up and call Method B.
So B would be executed now.
It will trend to the first line.
Hello.
It will print hello.
This is the think about it as and the output it will print hello and that comes and moves down to the
second line.
Second line is that it cursive way that it cursive call of the math.
It will call PPI, so it will go up and calls PPI as and then being executed and called.
So system to the print it will print again.
Hello.
It moves down here to P and P, it will call the method.
So again, it will go and copy and it will print hello on their cards.
So hello would be executed at this point and going down and so on again and again.
So this be this writing or this code will result in infinite loop.
So infinite loop of hello.
OK, so this is that encouraging.
This is one of the bad things that may happen to you is the unlimited, unlimited, unlimited calling
of the method.
So you need a stopping condition to limit this recursive.
Colleague of the method.
OK.
This is a quick example about the research.
Let's take another example about the.
We have.
And now a Method B and the main method, the main method is calling B, so B would be called above.
We have created a count zero integer count.
When you copy, go and increase count plus plus, so count now it's not zero, if there's one, if count,
which is one is less than or equal to five.
Go and do this.
Yes, it is less than five.
So it will print hello.
So this is the council.
And it will print hello, plus the count.
Hello.
Count count is equal to one.
OK.
And this will call again the P.
So it will increase count.
Plus plus.
It will become to if count less than or equal to five yes to less than or equal to five than print.
Hello.
Do and it will again call peace help.
It is a cold again.
Be above.
And being executed count plus plus cell count would be now three three if three less than or equal to
five.
Yes, go and print hello.
So hello.
Three.
And we execute this.
I call the method again.
It will increase the count by one, so it will become for.
If count for less than five, yes, system that out, the Brent Hello, Ford and go down to the pier
going up and call the method again, increase the count become five five less than or equal to five.
Yes.
So system print.
Hello.
Count.
Hello, five.
And then call the method, be again, go up and call it.
Increase the count by one count increase and become six six less than or equal to five.
No.
So stop doing this.
This program will result in five messages a loved one to tell Hello.
Five.
So this is the stopping condition.
Count the count.
So Count plays the role as a limiting behavior, a limiting or limiting variable that will detect how
many times that occurs.
The recursion well occurs.
OK.
In the next video, we are going to discuss the recursive versus.